<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>City on BeoPlace</title>
    <link>/tags/city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in City on BeoPlace</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Relic and Remembrance</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-18-relic-and-remembrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-18-relic-and-remembrance/</guid>
      <description>When we think of a war memorial or monument, we tend to picture bold statements in very public places – monumental arches, columns topped with statues celebrating victory: soldiers standing with bowed heads, minimalist engraved steles, a flame, perhaps, indicating loss or deep solemnity. Former Yugoslavia is scattered with its own unique spomeniks born out of the Second World War. Many are mighty, massive, stylized abstract structures, standing alone or set in cultured green spaces, imposing themselves on all that surrounds them and all who approach them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My place - urban but not</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-18-urban-but-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-18-urban-but-not/</guid>
      <description>I am picking the forest for my place in the city. It isn’t right in the city, but in walking distance from my house and you can easily take a bus there.
I like it because it is close and a world away from the city. It makes me feel relaxed and happy and it’s the best place to observe the major differences between the seasons. There are a lot of “places” in the forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Neglected Spaces</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-04-greenspace-belgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-04-greenspace-belgrade/</guid>
      <description>One of the many appealing features of Belgrade from this outsiders point of view, are the scruffy patches of land that occupy the spaces in between a spectrum of contemporary and post war developments. The forgotten places, unkempt playgrounds, graffiti inscribed spaces left over after planning (sloap), abandoned and unknown facilities etc. In some places this pervading cultural anomaly has been offset by creative enterprises, on the face of it their shelf lives appear limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My place, Car park, Cetinska</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-12-23-car-park-cetinska/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-12-23-car-park-cetinska/</guid>
      <description>On the face of it ‘my’ place doesn’t reflect typical assumptions, if such things exist, of what restful environments look like. I take it as a given that car parks do not feature in most people’s preferences when considering where to kick back. Nevertheless, ‘my place’ is a car park, or more accurately a car park that forms the space in which an eclectic assemblage of buildings and structures form a patchwork perimeter of businesses, bars and restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My place, Tas</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-12-11-my-place-tas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-12-11-my-place-tas/</guid>
      <description>Barely five minutes’ stroll from home, Tasmajdan is a modest park, but that seems fitting considering the scale of the city. It’s dominated at one end by Sveti Marko Crkve. Although constructed relatively recently, its architecture is based on the 14th century Gracanica Monastery in Kosovo, lending it majesty and gravitas. As the park stretches away, it is filled with towering aged trees beneath which lie children’s playgrounds, fountains, statues and sculptures, all connected by a network of paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato House</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-28-plato-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-28-plato-house/</guid>
      <description>When asked to write about ‘my place’ I knew immediately what to write about. It is the faculty of philosophy. Tree of life. Six levels up. We are all breathing together, joined by an idea so porous and idealistic but strong at its root. I say &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; because I am also a former student of this faculty, majoring in ethnology - anthropology. Although I graduated from college long ago, I always go back to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kursulina Street </title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-27-kursulina-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-27-kursulina-street/</guid>
      <description>The place that is closest to my heart in Belgrade is Kursulina street on Vracar. It is located behind the Sveti Sava temple and leads to Kaleniceva market. There are only a few cafes there; it is mostly old communist residential buildings on both sides. However, those buildings seem to have been a bit more luxurious than the other communist buildings that can be seen in this city, as if teachers, lawyers and doctors populated them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>