<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BeoPlace</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BeoPlace</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Place For All</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-03-05-tas-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-03-05-tas-park/</guid>
      <description>Tasmadjan is a park catering for all. It’s well located just out of town between the parliament and Vukov Spomenik. It has something for all seasons. A jogging path and workout area, cafes, paths, dog zones, kids’ zones, a stadium at the back and a church for when you feel spiritual. There are green lawns with trees throughout, some large and generous offering shade in summer. Apparently, it used to be a graveyard and has quite a history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relic and Remembrance</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-18-relic-and-remembrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-18-relic-and-remembrance/</guid>
      <description>When we think of a war memorial or monument, we tend to picture bold statements in very public places – monumental arches, columns topped with statues celebrating victory: soldiers standing with bowed heads, minimalist engraved steles, a flame, perhaps, indicating loss or deep solemnity. Former Yugoslavia is scattered with its own unique spomeniks born out of the Second World War. Many are mighty, massive, stylized abstract structures, standing alone or set in cultured green spaces, imposing themselves on all that surrounds them and all who approach them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My place - urban but not</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-18-urban-but-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-18-urban-but-not/</guid>
      <description>I am picking the forest for my place in the city. It isn’t right in the city, but in walking distance from my house and you can easily take a bus there.
I like it because it is close and a world away from the city. It makes me feel relaxed and happy and it’s the best place to observe the major differences between the seasons. There are a lot of “places” in the forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Neglected Spaces</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-04-greenspace-belgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-04-greenspace-belgrade/</guid>
      <description>One of the many appealing features of Belgrade from this outsiders point of view, are the scruffy patches of land that occupy the spaces in between a spectrum of contemporary and post war developments. The forgotten places, unkempt playgrounds, graffiti inscribed spaces left over after planning (sloap), abandoned and unknown facilities etc. In some places this pervading cultural anomaly has been offset by creative enterprises, on the face of it their shelf lives appear limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My place, Car park, Cetinska</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-12-23-car-park-cetinska/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-12-23-car-park-cetinska/</guid>
      <description>On the face of it ‘my’ place doesn’t reflect typical assumptions, if such things exist, of what restful environments look like. I take it as a given that car parks do not feature in most people’s preferences when considering where to kick back. Nevertheless, ‘my place’ is a car park, or more accurately a car park that forms the space in which an eclectic assemblage of buildings and structures form a patchwork perimeter of businesses, bars and restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My place, Tas</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-12-11-my-place-tas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-12-11-my-place-tas/</guid>
      <description>Barely five minutes’ stroll from home, Tasmajdan is a modest park, but that seems fitting considering the scale of the city. It’s dominated at one end by Sveti Marko Crkve. Although constructed relatively recently, its architecture is based on the 14th century Gracanica Monastery in Kosovo, lending it majesty and gravitas. As the park stretches away, it is filled with towering aged trees beneath which lie children’s playgrounds, fountains, statues and sculptures, all connected by a network of paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato House</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-28-plato-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-28-plato-house/</guid>
      <description>When asked to write about ‘my place’ I knew immediately what to write about. It is the faculty of philosophy. Tree of life. Six levels up. We are all breathing together, joined by an idea so porous and idealistic but strong at its root. I say &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; because I am also a former student of this faculty, majoring in ethnology - anthropology. Although I graduated from college long ago, I always go back to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kursulina Street </title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-27-kursulina-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-27-kursulina-street/</guid>
      <description>The place that is closest to my heart in Belgrade is Kursulina street on Vracar. It is located behind the Sveti Sava temple and leads to Kaleniceva market. There are only a few cafes there; it is mostly old communist residential buildings on both sides. However, those buildings seem to have been a bit more luxurious than the other communist buildings that can be seen in this city, as if teachers, lawyers and doctors populated them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Place, Zemun Kej</title>
      <link>/blog/my-place-zemun-kej/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/my-place-zemun-kej/</guid>
      <description>Living far away from home, family and friends makes me need a place where I can breath and find peace of mind. My place is a place, feeling and a necessity for me. The place is the quay along the river Danube, more specifically the end of the man made quay in Zemun. Zemun Kej is my paradise when walking there with my dogs early in the morning. I always meet the same few existences; the men who are standing on the brink with fishing poles trying to catch a fish or two, the stray cats watching the men begging for them to give them their smallest catch, the very cheerful lady who feeds the many swans with leftover bread from nearby restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>/portfolio/caramel-bottle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/caramel-bottle/</guid>
      <description>Communication Social groupings are a core aspect of what we generally understand to be community. The collective participation at places of work, neighbourhoods and clubs are what have been described as the webs that bind individuals, who would otherwise be on their own, contribute to the maintenance of civic social and moral order. Community is to many, the activity of sharing with and participation of commonly held goals that inspire a sense of shared stewardship of neighbourhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologies</title>
      <link>/portfolio/shopping-bag-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:58:55 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/shopping-bag-concept/</guid>
      <description>Useful and Limited It is expected that by 2040 the worlds energy supply will be comprised of four almost equal parts - coal, gas, oil and low carbon sources. Future targets for the reduction of CO2 emissions are not expected to be met and are actually expected to increase. The potential of technology as an amelioration measure is regularly cited in various forums. However this is a nuanced subject to evaluate and whereas technology is a valuable feature of CO2 reduction initiatives, it is not a panacea for the ailing planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept of Place</title>
      <link>/portfolio/makeup-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:57:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/makeup-element/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Place The creation of ‘placeness’ is an integral element of built environment design processes when attempting to re-negotiate the character of sites. Places are perceived to include psychological, social and human activities rooted within a physical setting, or put another way, placeness is the collection of symbolic meanings and the collective or individual attachment with a spatial setting. We attribute meaning to landscapes and consequently become attached to the meanings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience</title>
      <link>/portfolio/table-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:56:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/table-design/</guid>
      <description>The Resilience Perspective The relationship between human beings, the limited resources of the earth, climate change and the eco-systems in which we exist has broadly framed the discourse of sustainable urban environments. The notion of sustainability has undoubtedly influenced the general movement of built environment stakeholders to embrace measures that on the face of it reflect sustainable thinking, though this has not been consistent in regards to urban development. Accordingly, it has been observed that the S word (sustainability) is more and more being superseded by the R word that is resilience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now and Then</title>
      <link>/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:54:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</guid>
      <description>Yugoslav, Post-War As with many post-war European countries Yugoslavia was in the position of needing to rejuvenate its economy, industrializing urban regions through factory and office construction and not least of all housing the workforce. Consequently, urban populations grew rapidly as did the demand for flats, houses and offices etc. Unfortunately, the underdeveloped building technology was not equal to the necessary requirements of housing the increasing numbers of workers and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green and Space</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dew-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dew-drop/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Being with Nature The estimated exponential rise in urban population densities raises obvious sustainability concerns. Given the dramatic increase in city inhabitation it is increasingly important that people feel ownership and responsibility for shared public spaces. The emotional, cultural and social well-being of urban communities is dependent on numerous considerations and factors. The establishment of a sense of place and the role of ecology in achieving this is fundamental to the long term health or urban environments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>