<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Timer | Responsive Multipurpose Bootstrap Hugo Template</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Timer | Responsive Multipurpose Bootstrap Hugo Template</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:59:54 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>community</title>
      <link>/portfolio/caramel-bottle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:59:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/caramel-bottle/</guid>
      <description>Communication Social groupings are a core aspect of what we generally understand to be community. The collective participation at places of work, neighbourhoods and clubs are what have been described as the webs that bind individuals, who would otherwise be on their own, contribute to the maintenance of civic social and moral order. Community is to many, the activity of sharing with and participation of commonly held goals that inspire a sense of shared stewardship of neighbourhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologies</title>
      <link>/portfolio/shopping-bag-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:58:55 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/shopping-bag-concept/</guid>
      <description>Useful and Limited It is expected that by 2040 the worlds energy supply will be comprised of four almost equal parts - coal, gas, oil and low carbon sources. Future targets for the reduction of CO2 emissions are not expected to be met and are actually expected to increase. The potential of technology as an amelioration measure is regularly cited in various forums. However this is a nuanced subject to evaluate and whereas technology is a valuable feature of CO2 reduction initiatives, it is not a panacea for the ailing planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept of Place</title>
      <link>/portfolio/makeup-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:57:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/makeup-element/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Place The creation of ‘placeness’ is an integral element of built environment design processes when attempting to re-negotiate the character of sites. Places are perceived to include psychological, social and human activities rooted within a physical setting, or put another way, placeness is the collection of symbolic meanings and the collective or individual attachment with a spatial setting. We attribute meaning to landscapes and consequently become attached to the meanings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience</title>
      <link>/portfolio/table-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:56:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/table-design/</guid>
      <description>The Resilience Perspective The relationship between human beings, the limited resources of the earth, climate change and the eco-systems in which we exist has broadly framed the discourse of sustainable urban environments. The notion of sustainability has undoubtedly influenced the general movement of built environment stakeholders to embrace measures that on the face of it reflect sustainable thinking, though this has not been consistent in regards to urban development. Accordingly, it has been observed that the S word (sustainability) is more and more being superseded by the R word that is resilience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now and Then</title>
      <link>/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:54:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</guid>
      <description>Yugoslav, Post-War As with many post-war European countries Yugoslavia was in the position of needing to rejuvenate its economy, industrializing urban regions through factory and office construction and not least of all housing the workforce. Consequently, urban populations grew rapidly as did the demand for flats, houses and offices etc. Unfortunately, the underdeveloped building technology was not equal to the necessary requirements of housing the increasing numbers of workers and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green and Space</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dew-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:53:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dew-drop/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Being with Nature The estimated exponential rise in urban population densities raises obvious sustainability concerns. Given the dramatic increase in city inhabitation it is increasingly important that people feel ownership and responsibility for shared public spaces. The emotional, cultural and social well-being of urban communities is dependent on numerous considerations and factors. The establishment of a sense of place and the role of ecology in achieving this is fundamental to the long term health or urban environments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>